

- Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka,1229
 Bangladesh
- +8801868984364
- md.faisal3@northsouth.edu
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-faisal-ahmed-0298b2195/
- https://github.com/mdfaisalahmed025
- https://mdfaisalahmed.netlify.app/

SUMMERY

I am a computer science and engineering student who found his true passion for web development, especially back-end development. I specialize in Python and Django and have vital experience building websites and large-scale web applications using frameworks and libraries. Also, I have experience working with Node js, MongoDB. I love the combination of creative and logical-problem solving. And that's why I always try to apply my knowledge in building real-world projects. After all, I am passionate about learning new tools and technologies for building projects.

SKILLS

- Python and Django
- Node Js and Express Js
- Mongodb
- WordPress developer
- Seo Expert And Content creator
- HTML5, SCSS, BOOTSRTAP JAVASCRIPT
- Graphic Designer,
- Machine Learning
- Microsoft excel, Powerpoint, canva pro
- Git and GitHub
- Slack and trello

MD FAISAL AHMED

EXPERIENCE

September 2020 - Current

Seo Expert and Content Creator | Own

- Read and understand technical texts on the different articles and writing content
- Collaborated with network specialists to resolve security breaches.
- Improved web design and usability
- Managed online content using best practices in SEO to improve search rankings.
- Produced and updated website to facilitate daily visitors.
- Partnered with technical teams to align designs with hosting and site performance capabilities.

May 2019 - Current

Wordpress Designer | Own

- It was my own website where I worked for amazon affiliate marketing
- I am working on theme customization and different plug in
- Understood functional requirements and adapted design work accordingly.

ACADEMIC AND PERSONAL PROJECTS

Metro Rail Management System

We have created a web-based Train Ticket Management System based on Dhaka's latest Metro Rail Project. Our target is to create a reliable and fast experience for all Metro Rail passengers, Taking a step ahead toward the visionary project of Digital Bangladesh. It was built to have two kinds of users: passengers and trainmasters. Our web app has a bunch of functionalities that make the lives of passengers and trainmasters much easier as it makes their experience fluid and reduces their daily hassles. Passengers don't need to carry a physical ticket either, as we've implemented a very useful digital ticket feature with QR Code that can be downloaded from the passenger's phone immediately after the payment.

GitHublink: https://github.com/saadism777/Metro-Rail-Management-System

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

June 2019 - Current Sub-Committee | North South University Social Services Club

- Developed ongoing programs using good team communication and collaboration.
- Demonstrated consistent hard work and dedication to achieve results and improve operations.

EDUCATION

2018-2022

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Engineering North South University | Dhaka, Bangladesh Current Cgpa: - 3.06/4.00

2016-2017

Higher Secondary School Certificate | Science Govt. Science College | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Gpa:- 4.92/5.00

2014-2015

Secondary School Certificate | Science Lalpur Nazrul Islam High School| Dhaka, Bangladesh Gpa:- 4.92/5.00

Vaccine Hesitancy

Vaccinating populations is crucial to bring the amount of COVID cases down. One of the problems when vaccinating people is that many are hesitant to get vaccinated for various reasons. So if we could predict those who might be hesitant to vaccinate, there could be an effort to help reduce hesitancy. Our paper aims to do just that. We created a predictive model that takes advantage of data from previous work where they collected data from volunteers regarding how they perceive their healthcare system and vaccination in general. By using a machine learning model to predict whether a user is hesitant to get vaccinated or not, we can identify the ones that may be hesitant automatically.

GitHublink:https://github.com/mdfaisalahmed025/Vaccine-Hesitancy-Using-Machine-learning

Study Discussion

This is a study Discussion group where anyone can get access by registering with a valid email address and password. this project helps to discuss any topic, and anyone can create a room for discussion topics. In the room, anyone can document, and the user can see the replies of different users. There is a scoring system; whoever gives the correct answer will get a vote from other users.

GitHublink: https://github.com/mdfaisalahmed025/Study-Discussion-Project-

Bangla Hate Speech Detection

This work uses traditional classifiers, deep learning, transfer learning-based classifiers, or a mix of both types of classifiers to detect hate speech. Deep learning is a sort of machine learning that uses data to learn. It may be used to search for patterns in data. Transfer learning is a machine learning that allows a machine-learning algorithm to learn from data that another machine-learning algorithm has already learned. Pretrained approaches have significantly advanced machine learning and natural language processing disciplines, including hate speech identification. These methods were used to identify hate speech. However, we also used Google API to convert text from Bangla to English. After that, the emojis were removed from the data sets, and again that data were converted back to Bangla. Finally, we have the results where the best accuracy is in the GRU and the Attention model, which is 98%. However, the lowest accuracy in the BERT model is 94% for this research.

GitHublink: https://github.com/mdfaisalahmed025/Study-Discussion-Project-